

11929 West Airport Blvd, Stafford, Texas, 77477

🛘 +1 (713) 560-9777 | 🔀 afrolova@na.edu | 🖸 albinafrolova | 🛅 Albina Frolova

Summary.

Computer Science student offering a strong foundation in programming principles across multiple platforms. Experienced in object-oriented programming, developing, testing and debugging code, designing interfaces, and administering systems and networks. Ability to quickly learn and master new technologies, successful in both team and self-oriented settings.

Technical Skills: C, Python, Java, JavaScript, Swift, HTML/CSS, Angular.js, Bootstrap, Node.js, JQuery. Soft Skills: Leadership, team player, diligent and punctual, multilingual (English, Russian, Turkish, Kazakh)

Work Experience __

North American University

Houston, Texas

FOUNDER AND ORGANIZER OF HACKNAU

Oct. 2017

- Invited students from other schools to attend, reached out to student groups and departments on all campuses, launched a social media
- Put together a sponsorship prospectus. Booked mentors and judges.
- Full assistance throughout the whole event.

ITECH-STEM Houston, Texas

INTERNSHIP INSTRUCTIONAL ASSISTANT

Jun, 2018

- Assisted in facilitating the personal, social, and intellectual development of students.
- Helped each student with their assigned tasks and projects individually during each class period.
- Submitted daily report about every student's performance.

Suprex Learning Houston, Texas

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER INTERN

- Created, organized, and maintained Applications/System.
- Rendered complex software concepts in ways that can be understood by a clients and customers.
- Designed and implemented microservice, database, and APIs based on team conceptualization and service oriented architecture.
- Tested and deployed from development to production environments

IDEA-Lab Houston, Texas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Mar, 2019 - present

Feb 2019 - present

- Documented and tested new software applications, assessed new application ideas.
- Website and applications development.

Honors & Awards

Gold Medal in Hardware Control, "Infomatrix" International computer project competition

Silver Medal in Robotics, Young Inventors Project Competition (YIPC)

Almaty, Kazakhstan Astana, Kazakhstan

2017-2018 Best Computer Science Peer Mentor, North American University

Houston, Texas

Presentations

Environmental Service-Learning Conference

Astana, Kazakhstan

PRESENTER FOR <YOUNG INVENTORS PROJECT COMPETITION>

May 2016

• Introduced "Speak Gloves" project for deaf-mute people, which translated manual alphabet to letters and printed them in the iOS app.

Program Committees

2016 President, ACM-W Starter Lab Houston 2017 Secretary, ACM Club Houston 2017 Organizer & Co-director, HackNAU Houston 2017-

Computer Science Peer Mentor and Tutor, North American University present

Houston

Education

North American University

Houston, Texas

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

· Got an International Presidential Scholarship and President's Recognition Award.

August 2016 - present